Monica,that was the best Thanksgiving dinner ever.
這真是史上最棒的感恩節大餐
It was so good. I think you killed us.
太好吃了 你把我們撐死了
I couldn't possibly eat another bite.
我連一口都吃不下了
I need something sweet.
我要吃甜的
Does anyone want to watch TV?
有人想看電視嗎？ 好啊
Monica,your remote doesn't work.
摩妮卡，你的遙控器按不動
You have to lift it and point.
你得把它拿起來對準
Oh,forget it.
算了
Let's play that game where everyone says one thing they're thankful for.
你們知道嗎？ 我們應該來玩感恩告白遊戲
I am thankful for this beautiful fall we've been having.
我要說 感謝今年的秋天這麼美
Very nice.
說得真好
The other day, I was at the bus stop...
那天我在等公車
...and this lovely fall breeze came and blew this chick's skirt up.
突然吹來一陣秋風 把一個女生的裙子吹了起來
Which reminds me, I'm also thankful for thongs.
對了，我還要感謝丁字褲
The One with the Thanksgiving Flashbacks
本集播出：「感恩大回顧」
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
It's not so much an underpant as a feat of engineering.
與其說它是內褲 不如說是一種偉大工程
It's amazing...
效果那麼驚人
...how much they can do with so little material.
料子卻那麼少
And they play with your mind. Is it there? Is it not there?
它還會戲弄你 有穿嗎？沒穿嗎？
Are you aware that you're still talking?
你知道你還在碎碎念嗎？
Is anyone thankful for anything else besides a thong?
有沒有人要感謝 丁字褲以外的東西？
I don't know. Am I more thankful for my divorce or my eviction?
我不知道要比較感謝離婚 還是被趕出來
And I didn't think you'd be able to come up with anything.
我還以為你會沒得謝
I'm sorry. This is the worst Thanksgiving ever.
抱歉，這是最慘的一次感恩節
I am the king of bad Thanksgivings.
不行，我才是悲慘感恩節盟主
You can't swoop in with your bad marriage and take that away from me.
你不能挾失敗的婚姻空降 搶了我的寶座
You're not going to tell about your parents' divorce again,are you?
你又要說你爸媽離婚的事了？
Come on! I want to hear it.
別這樣嘛，我想聽
It wouldn't be Thanksgiving without Chandler bumming us out.
沒有錢德掃興就不算感恩節了
It's a tradition,like the parade.
這跟遊行一樣是一項傳統
If the parade decided it was gay and abandoned its family.
如果遊行也出櫃離家 拋妻棄子的話
「1978年感恩節」
Now,Chandler,dear...
錢德
...just because we're getting a divorce...
爸爸和我要離婚
...doesn't mean we don't love you.
並不代表我們不愛你
It just means...
只是代表...
...he would rather sleep with the houseboy than with me.
...他上床的對像是男僕 不是我
More turkey,Mr. Chandler?
小少爺還要火雞嗎？
Every time you tell that story, that guy's accent gets thicker and thicker.
你把那傢伙的口音 說得越來越重
So are he and your dad still together?
他們還在一起嗎？
No. After they got their own place, the houseboy got his own houseboy.
沒有，他們同居之後 男僕自己也有了男僕
Should have heard his accent.
你應該聽聽他的口音
You're right,yours is worse. You're the king of bad Thanksgivings.
你說得對，你的更慘 你是悲慘感恩節盟主
I've got one that's worse.
不一定，我有一次更慘
Really? Worse than, "More turkey,Mr. Chandler?"
慘過「小少爺還要火雞」嗎？
Did the little rich boy have a problem with the butler?
小少爺跟僕人有仇嗎？
Yes,mine's worse!
對，我的更慘
「1862年感恩節」
More bandages!
還要繃帶！
還要繃帶
Please,can I get some more bandages in here?
再給我一些繃帶
This man is
這個人快死…
Oh，no
不會吧
In this life,Phoebe.
今生的才算
Oh,this life. Oh,okay.
今生是吧
No,Chandler's is worse.
那錢德的比較慘
It must be cool remembering stuff like that.
記得前世的事一定很酷
I don't have any past-life memories.
我都沒有前世的記憶
Of course,you don't,sweetie. You're brand-new.
當然沒有，你是新生命
I know Monica's worst Thanksgiving.
我知道摩妮卡最慘的感恩節
Let's not tell this story.
那個就別提了 說嘛
I know!
我知道
It's the one where Joey got Monica's turkey stuck on his head.
就是摩妮卡的火雞 卡在喬伊頭上那次
Joey got a turkey stuck on his head?
什麼？喬伊頭上卡了只火雞？
It's not like it sounds.
其實不是那樣
It's exactly like it sounds.
其實就是那樣
「1992年感恩節」
菲比？
What's going on?
喬伊？怎麼了？
你看
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
I know!
我知道
It's stuck!
它卡住了
Step.
小心台階
How did it get on?
它怎麼會跑到你頭上？
I put it on to scare Chandler.
是我套上去想嚇錢德
Oh,my God! Monica's going to totally freak out!
天哪，摩妮卡一定會氣死
Help me get it off!
那就趕快幫我拿下來
Plus,it smells really bad in here.
而且這裡面好臭
Of course it smells bad. You have your head up a dead animal's ass.
當然很臭 你的頭塞在動物屍體的屁股裡
是摩妮卡
Did you get the turkey?
你替火雞塗…
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
Who is that?
那是誰？
It's Joey.
喬伊啦
Is this supposed to be funny?
你在幹什麼？你是在搞笑嗎？
It's not supposed to be funny. It's supposed to be scary.
不是搞笑，是嚇人
Get that off now!
馬上給我拿掉
I can't. It's stuck!
拿不掉，卡住了
It has to feed 20 people. They're not going to eat it off your head!
我不管，我爸媽的二十個客人 可不能就著你的頭吃
Hold on.
先別急
Let's just all think.
大家一起想辦法
I got it!
我知道了
You pull.
菲比， 你拉
I'll spread the legs as wide as I can.
我盡量把腿撐開
Now is not the time. Sorry.
喬伊，現在不要鬧 對不起
Count to three. One...
好，數到三…一...
...two...
...二...
...three!
...三
It worked! I scared you! I knew it!
成功了！我嚇到你了
I'm here,big guy.
大哥，我在這裡
Yeah,you are!
我知道
I scared you!
我嚇到你了
You did look like an idiot.
你看起來真的很白癡
I wasn't the only one who looked like an idiot.
白癡的不只是我
Remember when Ross tried to say "butternut squash"...
羅斯有一次想說冬南瓜
...and it came out, "squatternut bosh"?
結果講成南冬瓜
Yeah,that's the same.
的確一樣白癡
That's it. That's my worst Thanksgiving.
那就是我最慘的感恩節
That can't be the one Rachel meant.
等等，瑞秋說的不可能是那次
She didn't even know that happened.
她根本不知道那件事
So,what's yours?
所以是哪一次？ 哪一次？
I really don't want to tell this story.
我真的不想提這件事
Reliving pain and getting depressed is what Thanksgiving's all about.
講嘛，重溫悲慘的回憶 是感恩節的精神
For me,anyway.
至少我覺得是
And,of course,the lndians.
還有原住民的幫忙
Of all people,you do not want me to tell this story.
最不希望我提的絕對是你
What is that supposed to mean?
什麼意思？
「1987年感恩節」
-Monica,I think Rachel's here! -I'll get it!
摩妮卡，應該是瑞秋來了 我來開
Happy Thanksgiving!
感恩節快樂
Not for me.
我不快樂
Chip and I broke up.
奇普和我分手了
Why?
為什麼？
What happened?
怎麼了？
My parents are out of town, and Chip was going to come over.
我爸媽不是要出門 奇普不是要來…
And you were going to give him...
對，你要給他...
...your "flower."
...你的花芯
Monica,can you just call it sex?
摩妮卡，你能不能直接說做愛
It really creeps me out when you call it that.
你那樣講讓我渾身發毛
And by the way...
還有...
...while we're at it,a guy's thing is not called his "tenderness."
...在做的時候 男人的那裡不叫他的溫柔
Believe me.
相信我
Happy Thanksgiving.
瑞秋 感恩節快樂 你也是
天哪
Everyone...
各位
...this is Chandler.
這是錢德
My roommate...
我的室友...
...and lead singer of our band.
...兼我們樂團的主唱
羅斯
This is Monica.
這是摩妮卡
I'm Ross' little sister.
我是羅斯的妹妹
好
I'm so glad you could come.
歡迎你來
We've got plenty of food, so I hope you're hungry.
有很多吃的 希望你餓了
Chandler hates Thanksgiving and doesn't eat any Thanksgiving food.
媽，錢德痛恨感恩節 他不吃感恩節食物
I'm so glad you brought him here.
那還真是歡迎啊
I can make you some macaroni and cheese for dinner.
錢德 我可以幫你煮起司通心面
As long as the Pilgrims didn't eat it.
只要當年的清教徒沒吃我就吃
Damn it!
討厭
Does it feel weird around here now?
瑞秋，你會不會覺得怪怪的？
You know,since I've been away at college?
我去上大學不在了以後
Not really.
那倒不會
That's cool.
那就好
那你…
So that's Rachel,the girl you've been writing all those songs about?
她就是你那些歌的女主角瑞秋 對
Might want to rethink the lyrics to "She Feels Weird Since I've Been Gone."
你可能得修改那句 「我的離去令她渾身不對勁」
I cannot believe Chip dumped me for that slut Nancy Branson!
奇普居然為了那個花癡南茜 而甩了我
I am never going out with him again. I don't care how much he begs.
我再也不跟他約會了 他再怎麼求我也沒用
His begging days are over,now that he's with Nancy Branson.
他有了南茜，應該不會求你了
I've just had it with high-school boys.
你知道嗎？我受夠高中男生了
They're just silly.
他們只是些笨蛋
They're just silly,stupid boys.
他們全是些又笨又呆的小毛頭
I'll start dating men.
我要開始跟男人交往
I'm sorry,Judy.
茱蒂，對不起
I couldn't find that bowl you and Jack were looking for.
我找不到你和傑克要的碗
Call them Mom and Dad,you loser.
叫爸爸媽媽吧，俗辣
摩妮卡
錢德
Did you like the macaroni and cheese?
起司通心面好吃嗎？
It was great. You should be a chef.
很好吃，你應該去當廚師
好啊
Guess what.
你猜怎樣？
All this stuff about Nancy being a slut was all a rumor.
南茜很花癡的傳聞都是假的
Chip dumped her,and he wants to come over to my house!
所以奇普甩了她 他今天晚上想來找我
-That is so great! -I know.
太棒了 就是啊
Oh,gosh. Listen, if you and Chip do it tonight...
天哪，要是你和奇普晚上做了
...promise me you'll tell me everything.
你一定要把細節都告訴我
Totally. It's not that big a deal. We already kind of did it once.
那當然，其實也沒什麼 我們應該有做過一次
But now you'll definitely know whether or not you did it.
我知道，但這回你一定能確定
I know.
我知道
And Chip promised that this time it'd last at least for an entire song.
奇普還保證 這次會持續一整首歌的長度
I'm thinking of asking Rachel out tonight...
我晚上打算約瑞秋出去
...maybe playing her that song we wrote last week.
彈我們上周寫的那首歌給她聽
"Emotional Knapsack"? Yes. Right on!
「憂愁的背包」？ 對 漂亮
But don't take long. We're testing our fake lD's tonight.
不過不要拖太久 我們還要去試用假身份證
Right,Clifford Alvarez?
對吧，克裡夫艾維瑞茲？
Listen,Roland Cheng...
聽著，羅蘭陳
...if things go well, I may be out with her all night.
如果一切順利 我們搞不好不會回來
Dude,don't do that to me.
兄弟，別丟下我
It's cool,you can stay here. My parents won't mind.
沒關係，你可以留下來 我爸媽不會介意
It's not that. I just don't want to be stuck here with your fat sister.
不是，我不想整晚 跟你的肥豬妹妹在一起
Why don't you finish off these pies?
摩妮卡，把這些派吃完吧
I don't have any more room in the fridge.
冰箱塞不下了
No,thank you.
不了，謝謝
Judy,you did it.
茱蒂，你成功了
She's finally full!
她終於吃不下了
I called you fat?
我說你肥？
-I don't even remember that. -Maybe it'd jog your memory...
我完全不記得 或許唱...
...if you guys played a little bit of "Emotional Knapsack."
...那首「憂愁的背包」 可以讓你想起來
I'm so sorry. I really am.
對不起，真的
I was an idiot back then.
我那時候很愚蠢
I rushed the stage at a Wham concert, for crying out loud!
我還在「轟」的演唱會上 衝上台大叫
I can't believe you called her fat.
你居然說她肥
I can't believe you let George Michael slap you.
你居然讓喬治麥可賞你耳光
I am really sorry.
真的很抱歉
That is terrible. I'm so sorry.
我太差勁了 真是對不起
That's not the Thanksgiving I was talking about.
其實我說的不是那次感恩節
Yes,it was.
就是
No,it was actually
不是，我說的是…
Thanksgiving's over. Let's get ready for Christmas.
感恩節結束，準備過聖誕節吧 誰要去買聖誕樹？
I have the cutest Christmas story.
我有最可愛的聖誕節故事
We want to hear Monica's story.
我們想聽摩妮卡的感恩節故事
Mine had a dwarf that got broke in half, but,you know,whatever.
我的故事裡有小矮人斷成兩截 不過隨便
「1988年感恩節」
You changed your major again?
瑞秋，你媽說你又轉繫了
I had to.
沒辦法
There was never any parking by the psychology building.
心理系館旁邊很難停車
瑞秋
Love your new nose! Jack.
你的新鼻子真漂亮 傑克
What？ Dr. Wolfson's an artist.
怎樣？威爾森醫生是個藝術家
He removed my mole cluster.
他幫我點掉一堆痣
Want to see?
你要看嗎？
No! Please,let me.
我去開 不，讓我去
Happy Thanksgiving.
感恩節快樂
Your hair sure is different.
你的髮型變了好多
We were just talking about that.
我們剛才還在講
We can't believe how stupid we used to look.
我們以前真的好蠢
Where's Monica?
摩妮卡呢？
She's upstairs.
在樓上
Come down,everyone's here!
摩妮卡，快下來，人都到齊了
Ross,Rachel...
羅斯，瑞秋
...and the boy who hates Thanksgiving.
和那個痛恨感恩節的男生
錢德
Oh,my God!
我的天哪
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Is there something on my dress?
我的衣服有髒東西嗎
You look so different.
你變了好多好漂亮
Terrific.
That dress,that body....
那件裙子，那個身材
-Dude! -Sorry.
喂 抱歉
Yes,she's thin. It's wonderful.
對，摩妮卡瘦了，太好了
But we really want to hear...
但我們比較關心...
...about Ross' new girlfriend.
...羅斯的新女友
Her name is Carol.
好吧，她叫卡蘿
She's really pretty and smart.
她很漂亮，很聰明
She's on the lacrosse team and the golf team.
她是長曲棍球和高爾夫球校隊
Can you believe it?
很厲害吧？
She plays for both teams.
她兩個校隊都打
So I guess I'll see you at dinner.
錢德，那就晚餐見羅
-Dude! -Sorry.
喂 抱歉
Oh,my God!
天哪
That was so awesome.
真是酷斃了
You got him back for calling you fat.
你完全報了一箭之仇
He was drooling all over you.
他的口水流了滿地
-That must have felt so great. -lt didn't.
感覺一定很過癮 一點也不過癮
What？
什麼？
Yeah,I mean,I look great.
沒錯，我很漂亮
I feel great,and my heart's not in trouble anymore.
感覺很輕盈 心臟的毛病也沒了
I just don't feel like I got him back.
但我還是覺得沒報到仇
I just want to humiliate him.
我想狠狠的羞辱他
I want him to be naked,and I want to point at him and laugh.
我想讓他光著身體 再指著他大笑
That,we may be able to do.
好，搞不好可以
How?
怎麼做？
Guys tend to get naked before they're going to have sex.
男人要做愛之前都會脫光衣服
What?
什麼？
I didn't work this hard and lose weight...
我這麼努力瘦這麼多
...just so I could give my flower to someone like him.
可不是為了把花芯給他那種人
First of all,if you keep calling it that, no one will take it.
好，第一，你再那樣講 保證沒有人會要
And then second of all, you're not going to have sex with him.
第二，又不是要你來真的
You'll just make him think that you are.
只是要你誤導他
也對
I'll throw him out in the yard,lock the door...
等他脫光了 我就把他趕出去鎖上門
...and all our neighbors will just humiliate him!
讓所有的鄰居恥笑他
You'll definitely get him back.
那你就絕對報了仇
How do I make him think I want to have sex?
我要怎麼誤導他？
Here's what you do.
我知道了
Just act like everything around you turns you on.
假裝什麼都能讓你興奮
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Anything can be sexy.
就是什麼都能挑動你
Like this dish towel.
像…像這條擦碗巾
This feels so good against my cheek.
它的觸感好舒服
And if I get a little hot, I can just dab myself with it.
如果我熱了就可以拿它來吸汗
Or I can bring it down to my side and run it through my fingers...
或是把它放在腿邊
...while I talk to him.
邊跟他說話邊玩弄
I can do that.
這個我會
Good,good,good.
很好
Get busy. He's coming.
他來了
Hey,what's up?
你好
Could you make me some of that righteous mac and cheese like last year?
摩妮卡，你能不能幫我煮 去年那種通心面
I'd love to.
沒問題
I love macaroni and cheese.
我好喜歡起司通心面
I love the way this box feels against my cheek.
我好喜歡這個盒子的觸感
And I love carrots.
我好喜歡胡蘿蔔
Sometimes I like to put them between my fingers.
有時我喜歡把它們這樣夾著
Like this.
像這樣
And hold them down here while I talk to you.
然後放在腿邊跟你說話
And,you know,if I get really hot...
覺得很熱的時候…
...I like to pick up this knife.
...我喜歡拿起這把刀
And I put the cool steel...
把冰涼的刀身...
...against...
靠在…
...my body.
身上
Are you all right?
你還好嗎？
I'm fine. Just...
我很好，只是…
Twenty-year-old male.
什麼狀況？ 20歲男性
He's got a severed toe on his right foot.
右腳拇趾被切到
Could you please not do that feet first?
別撞到他的腳好嗎？
You know where his injury is. Severed toe,you just said it!
你明知他是拇趾被切到 你剛才也說了
It says the knife went through your shoe.
這裡寫說刀子刺穿鞋子
They're made of wicker!
那當然，他穿的是草鞋
Did you bring the toe?
斷指帶來了嗎？
I have it right here on ice.
有，在這裡冰著
Toes on Ice,coming soon to Madison Square Garden.
「冰上拇趾秀」 麥迪遜花園廣場即將演出
Save your strength,man.
省點力氣吧
Don't worry,son. We'll just reattach it and then....
放心，我們會把它縫…
What is it?
怎麼了？
You brought a carrot.
你帶了一塊胡蘿蔔來
This isn't your toe. This is a small, very cold piece of carrot.
什麼？ 這不是你的腳趾 這是一小塊很冰的紅蘿蔔
You brought a carrot?
你帶胡蘿蔔來？
Oh,my God!
天哪，
There's a toe in my kitchen.
我的廚房裡有一截斷趾
I'm sorry! I'll go get it!
對不起，我馬上回去拿
All we can do now is sew up the wound.
來不及了，我們只能直接縫合
Without my toe? I need my toe!
我需要我的腳趾頭
I can go really fast!  Dad, give me the keys to your Porsche.
等一下，我很快 爸，讓我開你的保時捷
I'm not falling for that one.
我才不會上當
That's why I lost my toe? Because I called you fat?
這就是我斷趾的原因？ 因為我說你肥？
I didn't mean to cut it off. It was an accident.
我不是故意的，那是意外
That's why for an entire year people called me Sir Limps-a-lot?
我就因為這樣被叫了一整年的 跛腳趾頭先生？
I'm sorry.
對不起嘛
It wasn't your whole toe.
又不是一整根腳趾頭
Yeah,well,I miss the tip.
我少了趾尖
It's the best part.
趾尖最棒
It has the nail.
趾尖有指甲
錢德
Sir Limps-a-lot.
跛腳趾頭先生
I came up with that.
那是我想出來的
You're a dork.
你好無聊
-I can't believe this. -I said I was sorry.
我真不敢相信 錢德，我都道歉了
"Sorry" doesn't bring back the piggy that cried all the way home.
道歉也換不回 我那思鄉情切的小趾尖
It figures that something like this would happen today.
我就知道今天會發生這種事
I hate this stupid day and everything about it!
我恨感恩節和這一天的一切
I'll see you later.
回見
Wait.
等等
Come here.
過來
Is there anything I can do? Anything?
有什麼我能做的嗎？
Just leave me alone for a little while.
有，讓我靜一靜
I'm a duck. I go quack-quack.
我是鴨子呱呱呱
I'm happy all the time.
一天到晚都快樂
Nice try.
別試了
Wait,wait,wait.
等等
Look,Monica
摩妮卡… 你看
This is not going to work.
沒有用的
I bet this will work.
接下來絕對有用
You're so great.
你真絕
I love you.
我愛你
What?
什麼？
Nothing. I said you're so great, and then I just stopped talking.
沒事，我說「你真絕」 然後就沒說話了
You said you loved me. I can't believe this!
你說你愛我，我真不敢相信
No,I didn't!
我沒有
Yes,you did!
你有
No,I didn't!
我沒有
You love me!
你愛我
No,I don't!
我沒有
Stop it,stop it,stop it!
別再說了
「1915年感恩節」
Gauze!
紗布！
紗布!
I need to get some gauze in here!
這裡需要紗布
Can I please get some more gauze?
請再給我一些紗…
This is getting ridiculous.
真是越來越扯了